[Music]
Hello, everyone.
TDSW YouTube Channel.
This will be the fifth episode of Getting started with GLSL on TouchDesigner.
Thank you for watching!
In this case... using rgb shift.
Like the one you're looking at right now.
We're going to make something where the colors shift to match the beat.
What we're going to do this time is we're going to use rgb to specify the colors separately.
Shifting the uv and shifting the color
Finally, this one is already out of the GLSL.
Use CHOP to generate parameters that change on a per-beat basis
That's what we'll be doing.
So let's get to it.
Place the GLSL first
Open this in your editor
The first thing we do is.
I'll put the value of this uv in the variable p
We want to start with black as the default color, so we'll use
I'm going to make some changes here.
VEC3
I think that makes it black.
sTD2DInputs[0].
I'll use r, g and b three times for convenience
I'd like to put it in a variable once.
It's a texture, so we'll call it tex.
sampler2D
Like this.
I'm getting an error with this one.
Once you use Movie File In
I can get you in here.
No more errors.
No bananas this time.
I'll use these flowers again.
The color of these flowers.
We're going to have to do r and g and b individually.
First of all, color.r's
texture(tex, p).r
If
Only the color red will go in here.
Similarly, color.g
Green.
If you do a g, you'll get a green color here.
Furthermore, if you do it with color.b, you can use
This is where the blue comes in.
Now, what you see in Movie File In and
The same one showed up here.
I'll try to comment out on this one.
In this state, it's just the green.
In this state, you said only blue.
It's like this.
We'll shift the uv from here.
Specifically, after the value of p
Enter the value of vec2
First.
+vec2(0.02, 0.02)
If you add the number
You can see the red has shifted here.
Let's change the numbers for a moment.
I'm off by a long shot.
The red one is off.
Now we're going to move the g's around.
This way, the g's are off.
I want to take it in the other direction.
in this way
Now r and g and b break down.
You'll see it displayed.
And while we're at it, let's move the b's around a bit.
Let's just say 0.04 or something.
Now we have a sentence state where the r, g and b are all off.
I mean, if you move it around like this.
The edges are a little off, and they're blackened by the slight shift.
The Zero part of this Input Extend Mode UV is
Yeah, like Repeat.
Let's just say Hold or Mirror.
I don't care which one, but I'll change it.
The basic structure is now complete.
Now we just need to get the parameters to pass to GLSL.
We'll try to generate it to the beat.
We don't need a little bit of code from here on out.
Make this one big once.
Too big.
We'll start by creating a value for the x shift
Beat CHOP came in.
Ramp is showing up now.
I'll show you the Beat here
This way you get four beats.
You'll get values of 0, 1, 2 and 3.
You can add a Logic CHOP to this.
When the value changes.
It's supposed to be like changing from 0 to 1.
Here's what this looks like on Trail
Every beat is a 0 is a 1.
That's how it works.
Here's how to trigger this Beat.
We want to generate random numbers, so we'll use
Add Noise CHOP here
Type is Random
Channel dx...
I want to output each rgb, so I'm going to use
I put in something like dx[RGB]
Time Slice On
It's like this.
A random value is created every frame.
Put a Hold in.
Firstly, Noise.
The second thing you can do is to add Logi.
Each beat generates a random number
That's what we're doing.
If you don't, you'll get another crack at it.
The numbers have changed.
You can add a Filter CHOP to this and add a
Like this.
Reduce this Filter Width a bit
About 0.65.
I'd like to try.
Now we see this Trail CHOP.
After moving towards 0.65 like this
It's a breeze to come back.
Multiply this by Math CHOP and you have these two things
Combine CHOPs Multiply
This will give you a smooth value.
It's now generated from random stuff.
Now add a Null to this.
Send this number to GLSL
Yes.
I'll make it uDX or something.
And if you put these three values in
thus
dxR, dxG and dxB
And these three are in now.
rgb
Like this.
If you use the value uDX in GLSL
A uniform float to use...
Not a float.
It's called vec3.
It's called uDX.
We'll put uDX into each of these x's
uDX.r
uDX.g and b and
Now you're in.
Now when this beat comes in.
When the rgb shifts
I got that x-direction ready.
Let's look at it a little larger.
It's like this.
This is the Beat CHOP.
This is.
From the place below called Tempo.
I can change the BPM.
There is one more way to do it, and that is to use the Dialogs' Beat
Here's something called the Beat Panel.
We'll just sit here and listen to the music.
By making the beat yourself.
Tempo is determined.
You can set your own BPM.
There is a feature called
I'll give it a shot.
You may not be able to hear this, folks.
I'm playing music on the other monitor.
That's about it.
The idea is that you can adjust the beat yourself a bit.
Basically, it's the same thing we do with this.
I'm going to copy this part.
Copy me.
This is the channel we're going to use.
We're going to make it look like we're going to make dy's stuff.
This is where the dy[RGB] came in, so
Merge here.
This value can now be used
dxR and dxG, dxB
dyR dyG tyB
It also contains the value of
I'm going to put this in here.
In dyG.
dyB and
These are the values that came in.
Like this.
The value that went into this uDY
It's like we're making a shift in the y direction here.
It's like this.
Now I think we've created the same one I showed you in the beginning.
That's it for this one.
In addition to the YouTube tutorials on TDSW
We offer live streaming workshops about two weekends a month.
Tickets are available through Petix and Eventbrite!
Also, TDSW uses Patreon
There are currently three plans available
You can find these links in the video overview section of the video
Check it out if you'd like.
Thank you for watching.
If you like it, please subscribe to our channel!
goodbye
[Music]